翻译 李SIR
翻译 阿蘅
翻译 天意
翻译 草草
时间轴 Imok
时间轴 大喷子
后期&特效  铭哥骑白马
校对&总监 天意
大西洋
帝国
『第四季 第十一集』
前情提要
我们第一次见面的时候  我说我结婚了
When we first met, I told you I was married?
我遇见你第二天 我就办离婚了
The day after I met you, i began divorce proceedings.
你让我有了一种久违的感觉
You made me feel something I haven't felt in a very long time.
什么感觉
What's that?
幸福
Happiness.
你买了份保单
I understand you've bought a policy.
你来干什么
What are you doing here?
我想确保客户的安康
I like to know what my clients are insuring.
你该感谢你父亲
You should thank your father.
他知道他所爱的一切
He knows that in an instant,
可能在瞬间
everything he loves
毁于一旦
...can be gone.
小心
Watch out!
快走  快走
Go! Go!
马赫里亚先生和我近期达成共识
Mr. Masseria and I have recently embarked on an arrangement
他会提供给我产品  运输路线经过坦帕
wherein he will supply me with product via Tampa.
用我的卡车运输
Using my trucks for delivery.
我他妈要我的分红
I want my fucking share.
我需要你把怀特先生
I will require you delivering your Mr. White
亲自带到我面前
to me personally.
我需要你派两位警官
I need you to send two sheriff's deputies
把朝琪·怀特带出镇
to get Chalky White out of town.
巴德反叛了  他现在是纳西斯的人
Bader's turned. He's in Narcisse's pocket.
他把自己反锁在办公室里
He's locked inside his office
准备一份声明
preparing a statement.
你为什么在这
Why are you here?
他在工作  伊莱
He's doing his job, Eli.
不然我为什么把他放在巴德身边
Why else would I put him next to Bader?
这是你想要的生活
This is the life you want?
我们不就是干这个的吗
Isn't it what we do?
过境了吗
We cross over yet?
过了一段了
Little ways back.
还有多久
How much longer?
快到了
We're getting close.
欢迎来到马里兰州  哈佛格雷斯
奥斯卡现在怎么样了
How Oscar keeping these days?
还好吧
Well, some and some.
谁都不会越活越年轻
Ain't nobody getting younger.
自然规律
Natural fact.
你怎么认识他的
How you come to know him?
他没说吗
He ain't say?
只说让我们去威明顿市郊接你
Say come pick you up outside Wilmington.
给你找些干净衣服
Get you some clean clothes.
我们都照做了
That's what we done.
你们要怎么看路
How you see the road?
不用看
Don't need to see it.
你们在这儿等着
You all wait here now.
他们就是小心行事而已
They're just being careful.
你为本诺先生工作吗
You worked for Mr. Boneau?
我跟几个流浪的小子打了起来
Got myself in a knockdown with some corner boys.
我当时
Way I was then...
总是找茬打架
I looked for a fight any old how.
都没感觉到剃刀砍伤我
Never even felt that razor.
低头一看
Looked down...
满手是血
hand full of blood,
血流不止
like... like I put 'em in a bucket.
都不知道那是我的血
Didn't even know it was mine.
还不停手
Just kept ragin'.
然后呢
What happened?
有个人出来
A man come out.
我从没见过他那样的人
I ain't never seen no one like him before.
他就那么过来
Folk just-- just move out his way.
那几个小子就吓跑了
Them boys fly off.
我说"先生  太感谢你了"
I said, "Sir, thank you kindly."
戴上帽子
Hat back on.
走不出三尺远就摔倒了
Ain't had the legs to walk three feet.
他趁警察还没来赶快带我离开
Take me away 'fore the police come.
给了我份工作
Put me to work.
教会了我一切
Taught me everything I know.
那就是奥斯卡
That Oscar.
恩赐的庇护所
Haven of Grace.
路牌就是这个意思
That's what it means.
出来吧
You can come on out.
下车啊
Come on.
你是怀特先生
You Mr. White.
你是谁
Who are you now?
你不是怀特先生吗
Ain't you Mr. White?
我还能是谁
Who else I gonna be?
我是温斯顿
I'm Winston.
大家都喊我拳击手
Everybody call me Scrapper.
我也不知道为什么
I don't know why.
我叔叔跟我说过你
My uncle told me all about you.
你地窖里有个臭鼬
There's a skunk in your cellar.
谁啊
Who is this?
你不想知道他叫什么吗
Wouldn't you like to know his name?
米恩斯  是你吗
Means. Is that you?
五万美元
$50,000.
你  去楼上看看
You, check upstairs.
你说什么呢
What are you talking about?
这价钱很公道了
A fair price, considering
-毕竟这一秘密能引发大麻烦  -米恩斯
- the incendiary nature of the revelation. - Means!
你大半夜叫我起来  几点了
You wake me up at-- what time is it?
七万五
75,000.
刚刚还是五万呢
You just said 50.
是吗
Did I?
你喝醉了吗  米恩斯
Are you drunk, Means?
清醒得很
Sober as a judge.
你到底想卖什么
What are you trying to sell?
信息
Information,
关于一个只有我了解的人
regarding a certain individual I am uniquely qualified to provide.
开门
Open up!
告诉我是谁  米恩斯
Tell me a name, Means.
二十万
$200,000.
-我要挂了  -五十万
- I'm hanging up. - Half a million dollars!
我没有武器  无法自卫
I am unarmed and defenseless.
是谁派你们这些阴沉脸的暴徒来的
Who has sent you grim-visaged thuggees?
梅隆部长吗
Secretary Mellon?
司法部长  还是那个乳臭未干的小鬼胡佛
The Attorney General? That unweaned whelp Hoover?
我们是美国国会警察
United States Capitol Police.
你们认为我犯了什么罪
What is the alleged transgression?
今年三月十四日在参议员委员会作伪证
Perjury before a Senate committee on March 14th of this year.
我的证词哪一部分受到了质疑
To what precise aspect of my testimony is exception being taken?
全部
All of it.
一切还好吗  老板
Everything okay, boss?
闻到外面有臭鼬吗
Smell any skunks out there?
他们不走沙地吧
I don't think they walk on sand.
那是什么河
What river?
萨斯奎哈纳
Susquehanna.
流进切萨皮克
Flow into the Chesapeake.
然后呢
Then where?
进入大海
Out the ocean.
穿过世界
'Cross the world.
随心所欲
Anywhere it want.
这河水多幸运啊
Ain't that water lucky?
椅子就在这儿
Chair's right there.
你在哪
Where you at?
在这儿
Right here.
过来点  让我看看你
Well, come closer. I wanna see you.
我知道你在想什么
I know what you're thinking.
-什么  -"他这是怎么了"
- What? - "The fuck happened to him?"
老了呗
Got old.
再老就进棺材了
Ah, as old as I'm gonna get, boy.
-这难说  -嗯
- Don't know about that. - Yeah.
你多久没来了  阿尔伯特
When was the last time you was here, Albert?
最小的孩子出生后就没来过
My littlest was born.
那有七年了
Oh, seven years?
九年了
Nine.
是她要结婚了吗
She the one getting married?
九岁的哪能结婚啊
You don't marry off no nine-year-old.
我可见过  在查尔斯顿的皇后街上
I seen it, though, back on Queen Street over in Charleston.
他们在那儿打过一仗
They fought the war over that.
才不是为了那个打仗的呢
That's not why they fought the war.
你这么聪明  说傻话呢
You're too smart to be that dumb.
你叫什么
What's your name?
道特
Daughter.
名字叫这个
That's your name?
是的  先生
Yes, sir.
我以前养过条蓝斑猎狗  我也没叫他猎狗啊
Had me a bluetick coon once and didn't call him Hound.
-你长什么样  -先生
- What you look like? - Sir?
我手放在面前都看不到
I can't see my hand in front of my face.
你得告诉我
You got to tell me.
-我  -她是个美人  奥斯卡
- I... - She a beauty, Oscar.
我不怀疑
I don't doubt it.
我一点不怀疑
I do not doubt it.
威姆斯  你在吗
Hey, Weems? You there?
-是  先生  -爱丽丝来了吗
- Yes, sir. - Well, Ayleese show up yet?
她放假
Her day off.
小猎狗  你会做饭吗
Hey, uh, Bluetick, you cook?
没办法才下厨
If I have to.
那快去吧
Well, you best get to it.
你们都跟她去
The rest of y'all go with her.
要我留下吗  叔叔
You want me to stay, Uncle?
那我就会说了
Ah, if I want that, I say that.
我告诉你东西都在哪
I'll show you where everything is.
-希望有围裙  -有的  女士
- Hope there's an apron. - Yes, ma'am, we got that.
你来这儿干什么  阿尔伯特
What you come here for, Albert?
照你说的做
What you told me.
我说的多了
Well, I told you a lot.
都不知道你听进去没
Don't know what you heard.
无论如何  不能相信白人
Never trust no buckras, no matter what.
也别相信黑人
Never trust no browns neither.
你都说对了
You was right on both counts.
你得现实点
You need to be realistic.
五十英里之内  再没这样的房子了
There isn't a house like it within 50 miles.
这可不是什么好事
That's not to its advantage.
而且你需要一名不问太多问题的买家
And you've needed a buyer who's not inclined to ask too many questions.
我们现在就是这样
That's what we have here.
三万七千不少了
$37,000 is a substantial sum.
-对我这种人来说  -对谁都不少
- For someone like me. - For anyone.
准将可不会这么想
The Commodore wouldn't think so.
路易会在逆境中尽力而为
Louis would make the best of a bad situation.
我可得拿这笔钱养孩子呢
I'll have to raise a child on it.
余生也都指着这钱了
Support myself for the rest of my life.
-你不是有新情人了吗  -什么
- Isn't there a new companion? - I'm sorry?
他怎么打算的
What are his intentions?
这可不关你的事
That's really not your concern.
这跟爱情无关  是关于钱
This isn't about love, it's about finances.
我知道你这方面一向精明
I've never known you to be foolish about those.
-或许我变了  -人很少变
- Well, maybe I've changed. - That rarely occurs.
如果你这么认为  利安德  我可怜你
If that's how you feel, Leander, I pity you.
我强烈要求你接受那个条件
I urge you to take the offer.
费里先生  我要是输了怎么办
Mr. Ferry, what if I lose?
总体来说  我们的案子还是非常
Overall, our case is still very--
但是输了之后会发生什么
But what happens?
上诉  当然了
Appeal, of course.
涉及到撒格斯基的条件是否合适
New concerns regarding the suitability of the Sagorskys,
还有环境正向改变的新问题
positive change in circumstance.
比如说  出售房屋
The sale of the house, just for example.
有足够资源的话  我们可以僵持好几年
With enough resources, we can tie it up for years.
-这段期间汤米在哪  -由你抚养
- And where is Tommy during all that? - With you.
由他们抚养  由慈善机构抚养
With them, a benevolent institution.
都有可能
Those are all possibilities.
特伦顿孤儿抚养院吗
The Trenton Home for Friendless Children?
说不准具体是哪一家机构
I couldn't say what particular institution--
你知道那里什么样吗
Do you know what it's like there?
-这没有意义  -因为我知道
- There's no point-- - Because I do.
我知道
I do.
我们这次谈话讨论的是未来
This conversation is about the future.
童年稍纵即逝
Childhood doesn't last.
一切都稍纵即逝
Nothing lasts.
他都不会记得
He won't even remember.
好几年吗
Years?
有如下条件你才会赢
The way you win things like this:
时间  资金还有坚持不懈
time, money, and persistence.
一旦抓住就不放手
Grab on and just don't ever let go.
知道对方的能力限度
Knowing the opposition's limited ability...
不断地投入资金
...to incur ongoing costs,
我们计划的时间越长
the longer we can draw it out...
乔·马赫里亚  迈耶·兰斯基  卢西亚诺
Joe Masseria, Meyer Lansky, Luciano--
拉吉  查理
Lucky, Charlie--
还有佛罗里达的那个人
and the one in Florida.
文森佐·佩德鲁塞利
Vincenzo Petrucelli.
没什么好讲的  我没见过他
Nothing to say. I never met him.
你哥哥呢
Your brother?
把一切都安排好了
Put the whole thing in place,
没给他选择的机会
didn't leave him a choice.
这个黑人  这个博士
This dinge they got, the doctor...
他们通过他做生意
they're running it through him.
努基听一个黑人的指挥
Nucky takes orders from a colored.
你是这个意思吗
That's the story you're telling?
金钱
The money, he--
他受不了金钱的诱惑
He can't walk away from that.
-芝加哥那边呢  -没参与这件事
- Chicago? - Not part of this.
每月给托里奥和卡彭一万美金
10,000 a month to Torrio and Capone?
只是在还债
Just paying off a debt.
好吧
All right.
纽约  大西洋城还有坦帕
New York, Atlantic City, Tampa.
这就够了
That'll have to be enough.
去工作吧
Get to work.
他不会上钩的
He won't bite.
我要让他们在一个屋里  伊莱
I need them all in a room, Eli,
跨越州线来计划共谋
making plans to operate in collusion across state lines.
是我的目的
That's what I came for.
你猜不透努基的心思
You don't know how Nucky thinks.
-你说他喜欢钱  -不足以让他收手
- You said he likes the money. - That won't stop him.
他总提到和平
He talks about peace.
他不是真心的  从来都不是
He doesn't mean it. He never has.
你欣赏那一点
You admire that?
你跟我们一起长大的吗
You grow up in our house?
用报纸当毯子
Newspapers for blankets,
晚餐偷土豆来吃
stolen potatoes for supper.
要不就饿肚子
Or nothing.
连续饿两天
That night or the next.
那种滋味永远忘不了
You don't forget.
你现在不饿肚子了
You're not starving now.
-他是我哥  -他不是你儿子的父亲
- He's my brother. - He's not the father of your son.
没让他进监狱  不是吗
Kept him out of jail, didn't he?
这个我说不准
I wouldn't bet on that.
克莱顿·戴维斯的判决马上到了
Clayton Davies' trial's coming up.
如果他的律师发现
What happens if his attorney finds out about the evidence
被人买通压下的证据怎么办
somebody was paid to suppress?
把这次会议开成  要不然
Make the meeting happen, or don't--
你自己承担后果
the consequences are for you to live with.
但是要记住
But just bear this in mind--
不管你有什么借口
whatever your excuse,
你跟我是一条船上的人
you and I are down this road together.
把这话跟那个忘不了过去的人说说
Explain that to a man who never forgets.
你浑身酒气
You smell of whiskey.
-跟你有什么关系  -别喝了
- What's it to you? - Lay off it.
我不喜欢酒鬼
You're no good to me like that.
烤面包
Crunchy toast?
是木莓果酱面包
It's raspberry jam.
听起来很不错
That does sound good.
你认识我  对吧
You know me, don't you?
你是奶奶
You're Mima.
但我是谁
But who am I?
我是你妈妈吗
Am I your mother?
不是
No.
她在哪
Where is she?
她死了
She's gone.
你爸爸呢
And your father?
他在哪
Where is he?
我不知道
I don't know.
我也不知道
I don't either.
太糟了是吧
Isn't it terrible?
你过来好吗  求你了
Would you come to me? Please?
别碰他
Don't touch him.
-你住在这里  -你不是
- You live here. - You don't.
你不会把我怎么样的
You wouldn't.
至少不会当着他的面
Not in front of him.
你离开就好
You just need to leave.
这是你和他的计划吗
Is this how you planned it with her?
抢走我珍爱的一切
To take everything away that matters?
我没计划任何事
I didn't plan anything.
但还是发生了
But it happened anyway.
是吉米的
They're Jimmy's.
他不应该有点
Shouldn't he have something
怀念他爸爸的东西吗
to remember?
不应该这样吗
Wouldn't that be right?
留好了
Keep these safe.
你手指上有个戒指
There's a ring on your finger.
是的
Yes.
你们俩
And you'll both...
好好照顾他
take good care of him.
到了
Okay, then.
那些人也一起吃饭吗
Are those men coming to dinner too?
他们是保护努基叔叔的
They keep an eye on things for Uncle Nucky.
海滩的天气真不错
Lovely day for the beach.
信天翁
怎么了
What's wrong?
大老远地来吃饭
Haul all the way out here.
他在示好
He's making a gesture.
对我们来说更不容易
Bigger effort for us than for him.
受不了你们两个
Honestly, the two of you.
你们好啊  伙计们
Ahoy, mateys.
-请求上船  -批准
- Permission to come aboard? - Permission granted.
厨房还需要帮忙吧
You probably need a hand in the kitchen?
不  一切都准备好了
No, everything's been taken care of.
谁想先去游泳
Who's up for a swim first?
-我想  我  -我先游
-I am! Me! - Me first!
屋顶修好了吗
You tend to that roof yet?
我会去修的
I'll get around to it.
-它自己可不能修好  -这是常识
- It don't fix itself. - Natural fact.
房子会归你的  温斯顿  你记住了
House goes to you, Winston. You mind that.
我跟你说  要修的地方可不少
A lot to look after, I tell you what.
房子是我姐姐尤拉莉亚的
House belonged to my sister Eulalia.
-为什么  -我名下什么都没有
- How that? - Don't keep nothing in my name,
什么都没有
not a damn thing.
她是我妈
She my mother.
-她什么时候去世的  -十二年了
- When did she pass? - 12 year now.
温斯顿需要有人来抚养
And Winston needed raising.
我可以给你找个地方  奥斯卡  你知道的
I'd have made a place for you, Oscar, you know that.
我不知道
I don't know that.
把你在镇上安顿好了
Set you up proper in town.
我不是无处可去  我来这是因为我想来
I didn't have to. I came here because I meant to.
你玩儿完了  就玩儿完了
When you're done, you're done.
是不是
Ain't that right?
这是常识
Natural fact.
跟你说
Tell you what.
安顿我  你看看你惹的麻烦
Set me up, with the mess you make.
没必要的话不要跟
Don't never do no business
那些白人做生意
with no ofay smile you don't have to.
他是你朋友  现在又不是了
He's your friend? Not your friend now.
不要跟那些
Yeah, don't ever go near no
纽约的自大狂走得太近
biggity da-da-da from New York.
全是口蜜腹剑
A lot of sugar up there.
你知道什么
What you know about it?
-就是一帮恶人  -现在不一样了
- Just a tangle of vipers. - It different now.
才没有不一样  阿尔伯特  都一样
It ain't different, Albert. It ain't different.
你们都有活力了  生活节奏变快了
You're all lit up and faster,
但都一个样
but ain't no different.
你忘了你自己是谁
And you forget who you are.
你跟一个寄生虫女人
You come runnin' down here with some
跑到这里来
easy rider woman by your side.
因为你不知道该走哪条路
'Cause you don't know which way to turn.
我说的对吧
Ain't that so?
对吧
Huh?
我是来找你帮忙的  奥斯卡
I come to you for help, Oscar.
瞧瞧你四周
Look around you.
我们在这里怎么帮你
How we gonna help you here?
我们全都要去海边
We all go down the shore.
干什么
And do what?
给他们洗澡
Wash them boys away.
有什么意义
Ah. Where your sense at?
不用吓我
Don't scare me none.
因为你没做过
'Cause you ain't never done it.
该死的 爱丽丝
Damn. Ayleese!
这鸡肉和老婆婆的阴部一样干
This chicken dry as Grandma's snatch.
-爱丽丝  -她今天不在  本诺先生
- Ayleese! - She ain't here today, Mr. Boneau.
站在那里的是谁
Well, who's that standin' over there?
你是谁
Who are you?
寄生虫
The easy rider.
寄...  蓝斑猎狗
Easy-- ah! Bluetick.
阿尔伯特  希望她值得
Sure hope she worth it, Albert.
反正她的烂厨艺一毛不值
She sure can't cook worth a damn.
我靠
Damn.
-你来了  -我本来想打电话的...
- You're here. - Yes. I was gonna call as soon as I--
我不在家
I wasn't in.
我出去了
I've been out.
到处走走
Just walking everywhere.
看看那些我多年未去过的地方
Places that I haven't been in years.
都很漂亮
It's all remarkable.
你没事吧
Are you all right?
没事
Of course.
-你没有...  -没有没有
- You're not, uh... - No, no.
因为不管有多困难
'Cause that's something you need to fight,
-你都必须全力抗争  -罗伊  不是那个
- no matter how strong-- - Roy, it's not that.
是
It's...
我感觉
I feel...
我自由了
I'm free.
我终于自由了
I'm finally free.
我知道这里不太方便
I know it's not convenient out here.
没有问题
Not a problem.
在这种情况下
Under the circumstances.
-我们依然一切  -照旧
- And we still keep everything-- - Looking normal.
该死的朝琪
Cocksucking Chalky.
他自作自受
He made his bed.
车里发生了什么事
The fuck happened in that car?
他逃了  躺在某条臭水沟里
He's on the lam, facedown in a ditch somewhere.
为什么  我没有警告过他吗
For what? Didn't I warn him?
我还坐在那谁的对面
And now I'm sitting across from... whatever he is.
-博士还是啥  -他在告诉我该做什么
- Doctor or something. - He's telling me what I have to do?
-告诉我  -就像你是他儿子
- Telling me. - Like you're his boy.
和平是他妈的无稽之谈
There is no goddamn peace.
上次我们勉强摆平
We squeaked by last time.
你准备好再来一次吗
You ready for that again?
我刚虎落平阳  这就是你的建议
I just roll over? That's what you suggest?
听我说
Hear me out.
让大家坐下来
Let's get everyone to sit down--
我们  纽约  佛罗里达
us, New York, Florida.
-共商大计  -就一点...
- Work out terms. - Just a friendly little--
那晚在丽兹  是你自己说的
You said it yourself that night in the Ritz,
同心协力  共谋计策
all work together, take the next step.
现在是时候了吧
Maybe now's the time.
结束这种状况  让一切还原
Get the rules in place, put an end to this.
我不住丽兹了
I'm not in the Ritz anymore.
你不想抢回来吗
Don't you want it back?
我想  全部拿回来
I want it back. All of it.
做好准备吧  努基  趁还有人可以用
Set it up now, Nuck, while there's still a hand to play.
你不信任谁
Who don't you trust?
-什么  -我们这边  你不信任谁
- Huh? - On our side, who don't you trust?
你为什么这么问
Why are you even asking?
因为好奇
Because I'm curious.
巴德
Bader.
巴德算个屁
Bader's nothing.
我会处理好巴德
I'll deal with Bader.
米恩斯说  我这边有内鬼
Means told me there's a skunk in my cellar.
那个司法人员
The Justice guy?
他自始自终都是个骗子
He's a bunco artist, start to finish.
他说二十万  你相信吗
200 grand, he says. Believe that?
-看吧  -他有什么
- There you go. - But what's he got?
钱给他  查清楚  你觉得值得
Pay him and find out, you think it's worth it.
禁酒探员
The Prohee.
-诺克斯  -你也关心过
- Knox? - You had concerns.
只是因为埃迪出了事
Uh... that was just during the whole Eddie thing.
谁知道出了什么事
Who knew what was going on?
你的看法是什么
What's your take, though?
据我所知  他喜欢钱
Far as I can see, he likes the money.
某天他会成为你的麻烦
Be your headache one day.
我的麻烦
Mine?
不过你可以处理好
And you can deal with all of it.
你要去哪里
You off somewhere?
妈妈问你把保暖锅放哪里去了
Ma wants to know where you keep the chafing dishes.
只是关于它的价值 不过没关系
It's a fraction of what it's worth, but it doesn't matter.
你自己说的  太大了
You said it yourself-- it's too big.
对这里来说太大了
It's too big for here.
那些人都不到城里来了
Those people don't come to town anymore.
毕竟是一大笔钱
And it's a substantial sum, after all.
大家真的需要多少钱呢
I mean, how much does anybody really need?
他会好起来的  他会的
And he'll be better off. He will be.
话糙  但是这是事实
It hurts to say it, but I know it's true.
也许某一天
And maybe someday...
我瞎扯呢
I'm nattering.
这不太招人喜欢
Not an appealing quality.
我住嘴  我吃东西
I'm stopping. I'm eating.
好姑娘
Good girl.
你做出了正确的决定  我为你高兴
Well, you made the right decision. I'm happy for you.
可你看起来并不高兴
You don't look happy.
是吗
I don't?
有意思
That's funny.
终于得到我想要的东西了
Got what I wanted, finally.
什么东西
What's that?
收购的事儿
Merger's going through.
A&P会以高昂的价格买下我们的产权
A&P's gonna buy us out for a pretty staggering price.
罗伊
Roy.
这让我有点不安
It had me on edge for--
其实很不安  我现在可以说
well, more than a little, I can say that now.
结果半路杀出个休森
Turns out it was Hewson who was standing in the way.
我  我不明白
I-- I don't--
我们还和他以及他妻子喝东西
While we had drinks with him and his wife?
-当你和我假装夫妻的时候  -是的...
- When you and I were married? - Yes, from...
从印第安纳来的那位
Indiana. Anyway...
他表面上说好听的
He was pouring honey in my ear,
可是从一开始他就反对
but he was against it from the start.
有大人物给他送酒
The muckety-mucks gave him the boot.
可他不低调  不过他后来一帆风顺
He didn't go quietly, but after that, smooth sailing.
律师们昨天签字了
The lawyers signed off yesterday.
对我来说是好消息
Big bonus for me.
我们庆祝一番如何
Why aren't we celebrating?
我不知道
I don't know.
我不喜欢结束
I hate when things end.
什么结束
What's ending?
我来这里的目的
What I came here for.
你要去哪里
Where are you going?
他们送我去哪儿我就去哪儿
Wherever they send me.
你对我撒过谎吗
Have you been lying to me?
-关于什么  -你的妻子
- About what? - Your wife.
我没有撒谎
I didn't lie about that.
那你要说什么
Then what are you saying?
你经历了太多
You have been through so much,
我甚至都无法想象的事情
things I can't even imagine.
你已经非常勇敢了  真的
You're very brave. I mean that.
此时你看起来非常美丽
And right now you look so beautiful.
真是个美好的道别
What an awfully gallant good-bye.
我不是道别
I'm not saying good-bye.
我是得离开
I do have to leave.
但我要你跟我一起走
I want you to come with me.
我要你嫁给我
I want you to marry me.
真的嫁给我
Really marry me.
这就是我的心愿
That's what I want.
那你为什么不问我呢
What's stopping you from asking?
刚刚不是问了吗
Hell, I thought I just did.
-他做什么呢  -我不应该说的
- What does he do? - I'm not supposed to talk about it.
-不能告诉你的家人吗  -我能吗
- If you can't tell your family... - Should I?
我得说  我们做事儿
I'd say we're all pretty good
都非常小心谨慎
at keeping things close to the vest.
-你们不能吧  -我会保守秘密的
- Not sure about you. - I can keep my mouth shut.
-不  你不能  -你刚刚都说漏嘴了
- No, you can't. - You just said something.
-我不知道已经开始了  -告诉我们
- I didn't know we started. - Tell us.
他锁了办公室的门
Well, he shuts his office door,
脱了裤子到处走
walks around with his trousers off.
市长
The mayor?
不想把裤子弄皱了
Doesn't want to get 'em wrinkled.
我觉得是一个会赢的竞选战略
Sounds to me like a winning campaign strategy.
不清楚  我觉得巴卡拉克会大获全胜
I don't know. I think Bacharach might beat the pants off him.
会把他赢得裤子也不剩
很好吧
Pretty good, huh?
下一站  钢铁码[娱乐场所]
Next stop: the Steel Pier.
大获全胜
"Beat the pants off him."
他可以去说相声了
He could be in vaudeville.
康凯特医生! 康凯特医生!
"Dr. Kronkheit! Dr. Kronkheit!"
我的脖子有风湿病
"I got rheumatism on the back of my neck."
-真像  -那是什么意思
- That's him to a T. - What's that supposed to mean?
动一下指头  就是世界末日
Every little sniffle, it's the end of the world.
这才不是我
This is not me at all.
那个买保险的肯定有你的电话
That insurance salesman sure had your number.
耍的他团团转
Played him like a fiddle.
你家出什么事了
"What happens to your family?
汤普森先生  我认识一个和你一样的人
Mr. Thompson, I know a fella just like you--"
凡事早想一步肯定没错
Nothing wrong with planning ahead.
真正的蓝眼娃娃脸
Real blue-eyed baby face, you know?
唱诗班少年那样
Choirboy type.
没想到他只想把最贵的卖给你
Wouldn't think all he wants to do is sell you the most expensive
琼  你能不能给我闭嘴
June, just shut your goddamn trap for once.
行吗  闭嘴
Okay? Just shut it.
别调侃了  就这样
Enough with the teasing. That's all.
给我在巴尔默来次约会
Got me a "Round-day-voos" In "Balmer."
别碰我
Get away from me, boy.
别让我找你麻烦
Don't let me keep you.
又一个小时  把手拿开
Ain't for another hour. Get your hands off me.
-然后继续玩你的  -住手
- Then play like you playing. - Stop.
就是不舒服
Can't get settled.
他怎么样
He doin' all right in there?
他累坏了
He get real tired around now,
但是不想躺下
but he don't like to lay down.
发发牢骚
Fussin'.
-老小孩一样  -什么
- Old man and a baby. - What's that?
老人和小孩一样
Different and the same.
小孩还有一辈子要走
Baby got their whole life in front of 'em.
而且不会花钱就能啃奶子
Plus he ain't got to pay to suck on no tittie.
这话别说出来
Keep your problems to yourself.
你想打架吗
You gonna make a move?
你赢了  回头见
You win. I'll see you browns later.
你这次再喝大了我也不去开车接你
Ain't driving down to fetch you this time you get all lushed.
要玩吗
Gonna play?
猜吧
Call it.
人头
Heads.
你是黑方
You're black.
好吧
All right now.
你是大人物
So you the biggety man?
-怎么讲  -叔叔说的
- How that? - Uncle say.
-我有自己的生意  -给我讲讲你的事
- I do my business. - Tell me all about you.
是吗
That so?
比如你怎么伤的
Like you blood.
那么
Well...
我们得回去
we go back.
我什么都不怕
I ain't afraid or nothin'.
到你了
Your move.
你来玩一会
Why don't you play a while?
不喜欢我做的菜
Doesn't like my cooking.
口味不一样而已
From a different time, that all.
是吗
Is he, though?
我们在做什么
What are we doing?
-等待  -等什么
- Waiting. - For what?
你有家  有个待嫁的女儿
You got a family, a girl getting married.
现在这些对我来说还有什么意义
What that matter to me now?
你只想着退出
You only think you quit.
我难道不知道自己的想法吗
Don't I know what I feel?
你想那些人死
You want those men dead.
你的敌人  和被你看成是朋友的那个人
The one who's your enemy and the one you called a friend...
不是吗
don't you?
你不过是个睡在摇篮里的宝贝
You wasn't nothing but a baby in that Storyville crib.
-不是  -是谁救了你
- No. - Who the man that save you?
我告诉过你  是医生
I told you. The doctor.
那又是谁害死你母亲的
And who the man steal your mama life away?
我不知道我的名字
I didn't know my name.
他叫我道特  我就是道特
He called me Daughter, and that's who I am.
我们走吧
Let's leave.
现在就走
Right now.
我们离开这里  再也不回来
Let's run and never look back.
你只要答应就可以
All you gotta do is say it.
叔叔找你
Uncle looking for you.
他很不安心
He real restless.
-你能选择去哪吗  -你喜欢哪
- Do you get to choose where? - Well, where would you like?
离这越远越好
Whatever is farthest from here.
-日本  -稍微近点的
- Japan. - Closer, please.
加利福尼亚
Uh, California.
我们的房子会是什么样的
What's our house gonna look like?
比你现在的小点
It'll be smaller than the one you have now.
-不  但是不要太小  -我会保证让你住着舒服的
- No, but not too small. - No, I'll make sure it suits you.
我自己也有钱
I'll have my own money, you know.
你就自己留着需要的时候用吧
You're gonna hold on to that for when you need it.
你想让我依靠你
You want me depending on you.
我想让你感觉和现在一样自由
I want you to feel as free as you do right now.
我们该走了
We should go.
我把车开出来  方便你上车
I'll pull up. It'll be easier to get in.
钥匙不见了
The key's hiding somewhere.
在这
Here.
菲利普斯
Phillips.
-罗伊  -在
- Roy. - Yeah.
菲利普斯
Phillips.
休森
Hewson.
-你来干什么  -庆祝
- What brings you here? - Celebrating?
刚吃完晚餐
Just having dinner.
-你和你的婊子一起  -这话太过分了
- You and your whore there. - Hey, that's over the line.
我过分
I'm over the line?
我因为你失去了工作
I lost my job because of you,
你这个背后下刀的混蛋
you backstabbing prick.
都十五年了
After 15 years.
-罗伊  别这样  -我现在还有什么
- Roy, don't. - What do I have now?
我这就让你感受下生活被毁掉的感觉
I'll show you how it feels to have your life ruined.
-你给我退后  -罗伊  别
- You back off. - Roy, no.
-罗伊  -我要让你知道失去一切的
- Roy. - I'll show you how it feels to lose everything--
我以为他会
I thought he would--
我以为他有
I thought he had a...
罗伊  我们该走了
Roy, we need to go.
-我们该走了  -我不该开枪的
- We need to go. - I should hang on to that.
去开车  赶紧  快去
You need to drive. Go. Hurry.
上车
Get in.
快点
Hurry.
你被抓住了
You're caught.
别担心  我们会一起受罚
Don't worry, we'll both go down together.
你觉得刚才是怎么回事
What do you think that was about?
我不会太当回事
I wouldn't take it too seriously.
你父亲脾气就是比较冲
It's always been pretty easy to get your father's goat.
真的吗
Really?
你跟他提玛丽·安·诺兰试试
Just mention Mary Anne Nolan to him.
-那是谁  -八年级的时候爱上的姑娘
- Who's she? - Eighth grade crush.
他给她写了首诗
He wrote her a poem.
我看到的时候真是乐坏了
Happy day when I found it.
不能怪他担心
Can't blame him for worrying, though.
你得想想你离开之后会是怎样
You have to think about what's gonna happen after you're gone.
为了你们全家好
For the sake of all of you.
那个卖保险的
That insurance fella, though--
听上去很像个骗子
sounds like a real sharpie.
我没怎么听全
I didn't hear very much of it.
-你见过他  -打了个照面
- You met him? - Just for a minute.
和你母亲说的一样
Like your mother said?
-什么  -娃娃脸
- What? - Baby face?
算是吧
Yeah, I guess.
以前见过他吗
Ever see him before?
没有
No.
你确定
You're sure now?
你和我说的话  威尔  跟谁也别提
Whatever you tell me, Will, it's just between us.
这个我们之前就说过了
That's what we agreed to.
努基伯父  我
Uncle Nucky, I...
该死
Shit.
我什么也没看到
I don't notice anything.
只是在感受海风
Just taking in the breeze.
姑娘们和我把一切都收拾好了
The girls and I put everything away.
你不用这么做
You didn't have to do that.
看着干净了我心理舒服
I feel better knowing the place is tidy.
我睡不着
I can't hardly sleep.
这些多余的时间
All this, uh, extra time,
老了之后无事可做的时间
you know, when you get old, you ain't got nothing to do with it.
你说了  该做的都做了
You said done was done.
是啊  可是这不意味着我得喜欢这样
Yeah, but it don't mean I have to like it.
给孩子们一些活干
Got the boys runnin' some action.
酿点私酒  搞搞赌局
You know, a little moonshining, some numbers--
但是没多少钱
eh, but it don't amount to much.
你的钱去哪了
Where your money go?
我本来挣的就不多
I didn't make half as much as you think.
准将给我什么我就接什么
I took in what the Commodore let me take in.
没多少选择
I had no choice.
他死了  三年了
He gone now, three year back.
我可不想念他  一点也不想
Man, I don't miss him. I do not miss him.
但是你在和那个叫汤普森的做生意
But you did your business with the Thompson boy, though.
-帮了他不少忙  -是啊
- Help him plenty. - Mm-hmm.
他怎么回报你的
Now how did that buckra pay you back?
我现在该做什么  奥斯卡
What I do now, Oscar?
你待在这  干出一番事业
You stay here, you build something up.
这是你侄子的地方
That's for your nephew.
温斯顿没什么大出息
Winston ain't never gonna amount to nothing.
你待在这  趁那个女人没给你惹上麻烦之前
You stay here, and cut that woman loose
把她赶走
'fore she do you in proper.
她和这事没关系
She ain't to blame for this.
如果不是她  那就是你
And if she ain't, then you are.
算了  你想怎样就怎么样
Well, damn, you do what you want.
最后结果都是一样的
It all winds up the same anyway.
这话什么意思
What that mean?
等到那一天到来的时候  大家都会四散而逃
The day come, everybody gonna run out of road.
-有什么要说的吗  -什么
- Any parting words? - Like what?
-我们  -我们很感谢您
- We... - We thank you, sir,
-邀请我们  -应该的
- for having us. - Long overdue.
你妈妈做什么事都快手快脚的
Anyway, your mother wound up doing everything.
好了  你可以走了
All right, you're free.
他又开始喝酒了
He's drinking again.
我希望他没有
I wish he wouldn't.
脾气又大了
Puts him in a mood.
威利还退学了
Willie quitting school.
想让我和他谈谈吗
Would you like me to talk to him?
不用了  一切都会好的
No. It'll all be fine.
谢谢你让我放松了一天
Thank you for a day off.
伊莱
Eli.
什么事
What's up?
告诉我你想听什么
"Tell me what you want to hear
我会轻轻告诉你
I'll whisper softly in your ear
我愿意做一切事情
All the things I'll pledge to do
证明我对你的真情
To prove to you my heart is true."
别这样
Ah, come on.
提这个干什么
Bringing that up for?
看看你的反应
To see how you react.
我当时十三岁
I was 13.
她长的又很可爱
She was cute.
也许我是嫉妒
Maybe I was jealous.
是吗
You were?
我没能赢下海滩巡逻杯
I didn't win the beach patrol cup.
你在其它方面有擅长
You were good at other things.
你建议的  那个会议
What you suggested-- the meeting.
我想过了
I thought it over.
你来组织  越快越好
You put it together, soon as you can.
好
Yeah.
我觉得这是解决问题的最好方案
I think it's the best way out of this.
我醒了
I'm awake.
感觉很有意思
It feels so funny.
为什么
How that?
就好像
Like...
一片云
a cloud...
在寻找天空
that's looking for the sky.
明天  我们按你说的做
Tomorrow, we do what you say.
天亮就走
First light.
什么
What?
我们离开
We go.
再不回来
Don't turn back.
我以为我听到车声了
I thought I heard a car,
但是外面什么都没有
but there's nothing out there.
没人看到我们  我保证
No one saw us, I'm sure of that.
你都没碰你的酒
You haven't touched your drink.
-什么  -喝吧
- What? - Go ahead.
你需要这个
You need it.
我做了什么
What did I do?
-我做了什么  -他要杀了我们
- What did I do? - He was going to kill us.
-我并不确定  -那他等在那里干什么
- I don't know that. - Why else was he waiting there?
我不知道他要干什么
I don't know what he was gonna do.
他没有枪
There wasn't a gun.
我杀了人  杀了人
I killed a man. I took his life.
我该怎么做
How do you do this?
做什么
Do what?
我是该打电话给警察然后等在这里
Do I call the police and wait here--
你不能报警
You're not calling the police.
-他就躺在停车场  -你不能报警
- He's lying on the pavement-- - You can't call the police.
不能逃跑
You can't go away.
-你听到了吗  -太迟了
- You hear me? - It's too late.
我必须这么做  抱歉
I have to, I'm sorry.
罗伊
Roy.
没人看到
No one was there.
没人知道
No one knows.
你只能
You can just...
把这事忘了
let it go.
-什么  -忘了这事
- What? - Just let it go.
忘了它
Get away... with it.
没人看到你
No one saw you.
我看到了
I saw me.
-上帝看到我了  -你能承受这一切
- God saw me. - You can live with it.
-你不了解  -我了解
- You can't know that. - Yes, I can.
我不明白
I don't understand.
当时没人支持我
There was no one for me.
没人来救我
No one coming to save me.
为了生存
There were things I had to do
我必须做一些事情
to survive.
你在说什么
What are you saying?
我
I...
死在这里的不是我儿子
It wasn't my son who died here.
是个男孩
It was a boy.
无辜的男孩
An innocent boy.
我
I...
淹死了他
...drowned him.
我编了个故事
I made up a story.
把他的尸体烧了
Turned his body to ash.
你和我在这里
You and I are here
我们在一起
together.
这才是最重要的
That's all that matters.
别离开我
Don't leave me.
他是谁
Who was he?
他的名字
His name...
叫罗杰
was Roger.
你什么都能承受的了
You can make yourself live with anything.
听到了吗
You get that?
听到了
I did.
-大卫  -非常清楚
- David? - Loud and clear.
-吉莉安  -罗伊
- Gillian. - Roy?
你给我听清楚了
I need you to listen carefully.
我是平克顿私人侦探所的
I'm with the Pinkerton Detective Agency.
这些人是我的助手
These men are my associates
也是你供认一级谋杀罪的证人
and a witness your confession to first-degree murder.
-但是我们说好要去加利福尼亚的  -他们会在
- But we're going to California. - As they will duly testify
-法庭出庭作证  -我们要去加利福尼亚的
- in a court of law. - We're going to California.
不
We are not.
我是被雇佣来完成工作的
I was hired to do a job.
现在  工作完成了
And now that job's done.
我欠路易一些东西
I owed Louis something.
我想你能明白
I'm sure you can understand that.
你真的是一个很有勇气的女人
You really are a courageous woman.
不  你不是
No, you don't!
我抓住她手了  抓住她另一只手
I got her arm. Get her other arm.
别再走了
Don't go no further.
是我  阿尔伯特
It's me, Albert.
你在这里干什么
What you doing out here?
睡不着
Can't sleep.
拿着猎枪干什么
Why you got the shotgun?
你的蓝斑猎狗走了
Your Bluetick gone.
什么
What?
她走了
She gone.
你怎么知道
How you know that?
我能听到这屋子里的一切声音
I know every sound this house make...
包括离开的声响
including the leaving kind.
你没阻止她
You ain't stop her.
我为什么要阻止她
Why would I?
别动  艾米特
Stay, Emmett.
不想猜到你
Don't want you underfoot.
你在干什么
What you doing?
奥斯卡
Oscar.
威姆斯才没去巴尔的摩
Weems ain't go to no Baltimore.
奥斯卡
Oscar.
别在晚上走远了
Don't walk off in the dark.
你想要什么
What you want?
这不是你的地方
This ain't your place.
你来这干什么
Why you here?
你最好谁清楚
You best announce it.
姑娘
The girl!
这里没姑娘
Ain't no girl here.
那就要另外一个
Then we take the other one.
你大可以试试看
You might try it.
-该死  -绕过去
- Fuck! - Go around!
抓住他
Get him now!
趴下  趴下
Get down! Get down!
别犯傻
Don't go and act foolish now.
快点
Come on!
把你的头带给博士
Your nappy head on the doctor's desk!
-小心  -天呐
- Look out! - Oh, jeez!
快跑
Run now!
混蛋
Motherfucker!
我告诉他我怎么样了
I told him how I was.
告诉他了
Told him.
我记得我告诉过你电话要早打
I thought we said these calls were gonna be earlier.
忘记看时间了
Lost track of time.
忙什么呢
Doin' what?
想事情
Thinking.
想的越晚越麻烦
The later it gets, the worse that is.
在想什么
Well, what's on your mind?
你不说话咱俩聊不下去啊
It's not a conversation unless you say something.
我想金盆洗手
I want out.